<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<sect1 id="Whitehead"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Whitehead</title>

  <para>Escrito por Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Configuração</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Tipo de Baralho</entry>
	  <entry>Baralho Padrão</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Monte</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing on to the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a
	    time to Waste.  No redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Descarte</entry>
	  <entry>A serem retiradas do monte. Carta no topo disponível para jogar.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Fundação</entry>
	  <entry>Quatro pilhas superiores direita. Forme as pilhas por naipes do ás ao rei. A carta do topo de cada fundação pode ser jogada de volta ao tabuleiro.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Tabuleiro</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles.  Deal all cards face up such that there is one
	    card in the first pile, two in the second pile, ending with
	    seven in the seventh pile.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Objetivo</title>

  <para>Mova todas as cartas para as pilhas fundação.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Regras</title>

  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by same color.  Builds of cards
    that are the same suit and in sequence can be moved as a unit.
    Empty Tableau slots can be filled with any card or build of cards.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped from the Stock to the Waste individually.  Top
    card in Waste is in play.  There are no redeals.
  </para>
  <para>Fundações são construídas por naipe de ás ao rei. Cartas nas fundações ainda estão em jogo. Clique duplo numa carta irá movê-la para a pilha fase apropriada se tal movimento for válido.</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Pontuação</title>

  <para>Você ganha um ponto por cada carta nas pilhas de fundação.</para>
  <para>Máxima pontuação possível: 52</para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Estratégia</title>

  <para>
    Empty Tableau slots are a prized commodity in this game.  Sometimes
    keeping them around until you need them is a very good idea.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>
