<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<sect1 id="Union_Square"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>1999</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>rwsy@mit.edu</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Union Square</title>

	<para>Geschrieben von Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Spielaufbau</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Art des Kartensatzes</entry>
		<entry>Doppelblatt</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Talon</entry>
		<entry>Ablage oben links. Der Rest des Kartensatzes wird nach dem Geben des Spieltisches hier abgelegt. Karten werden einzeln auf den Reststapel aufgedeckt. Keine Neuverteilungen.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ablage</entry>
		<entry>Es wird vom Talon gespielt. Die oberste Karte ist für das Spiel verfügbar.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Kartenreihe</entry>
		<entry>
			Deal face up a four by four grid for the Tableau, making sixteen piles.
			Top card of each pile available for play.
		</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Fundamentstapel</entry>
		<entry>
			Four piles on the right.  Foundation piles are built by suit from Ace to
			King, then King back to Ace.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Ziel des Spiels</title>

	<para>Verschieben Sie alle Karten auf die Fundamentstapel.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Regeln</title>

	<para>
		Cards in Tableau can be built either up or down in suit.  However, each
		pile must follow only one of these rules.  For example, if a Tableau
		pile has a three of clubs over a two of clubs, one can only play a four
		of clubs on this pile.  Any available card can be played on to an empty
		Tableau pile.
	</para>
	<para>
		Foundation piles are to be built in suit from Ace to King, followed by
		another King, then back down to Ace, giving 26 cards per pile when game
		is won.  Cards in Foundation piles are no longer in play.
	</para>
	<para>Karten werden einzeln vom Talon auf den Restestapel umgedreht. Die oberste Karte des Restestapels ist im Spiel. Es gibt keine Neuverteilungen.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Punktwertung</title>

	<para>Jede Karte, die in den Fundamentstapeln abgelegt wird, erzielt einen Punkt.</para>
	<para>Maximal erzielbare Punkte: 104</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Strategie</title>

	<para>
		A string of beads can be added to from both ends, and so should your
		piles.  Make good use of any empty slots to append cards.  With a little
		perseverance, this game can be a lot of fun!
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>
