<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd">
<sect1 id="Yield"><!--<sect1info>
		<copyright>
			<year>2001</year>
			<holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
			<surname>Yuen</surname>
		</author>
		<address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
	</sect1info>-->

	<title>Yield</title>

	<para>Geschrieben von Rosanna Yuen</para>

	        <sect2><title>Spielaufbau</title>


	<informaltable>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<tbody>
	<row>
		<entry>Art des Kartensatzes</entry>
		<entry>Standard-Kartensatz</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Talon</entry>
		<entry>Ablage oben links. Der Rest des Kartensatzes wird nach dem Geben des Spieltisches hier abgelegt. Karten werden einzeln auf den Reststapel aufgedeckt. Keine Neuverteilungen.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Ablage</entry>
		<entry>Karten werden vom Talon genommen. Die oberste und unterste Karte sind im Spiel.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
		<entry>Kartenreihe</entry>
		<entry>
			Deal cards face up in seven overlapping rows starting with seven cards on the
			first row, decreasing by one per row and staggering the piles as to
			achieve an inverted pyramid.
		</entry>
	</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Ziel des Spiels</title>

	<para>Entfernen Sie alle Karten.</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Regeln</title>

	<para>
		All exposed cards in the pyramid are available for play.  Kings can be
		removed singly.  All other cards can be removed in pairs that add up to
		treize with Aces equal to 1, Jacks equal to 11, and Queens equal to 12.
	</para>
	<para>
		Cards can be flipped singly from the Stock to the Waste.  Top and bottom
		cards are available for play either by themselves or with the available
		cards in the pyramid.  The top card of the Waste can also be played with
		the second card on the Waste.  There is no redeal.
	</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Punktwertung</title>

	<para>Jede entfernte Karte erzielt einen Punkt.</para>
	<para>Maximal erzielbare Punkte: 52</para>

	        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Strategie</title>

	<para>
		Removing the bottom of the inverted pyramid is the hard part.  Once that
		is achieved, it is sometimes better to remove cards from the Waste than
		the inverted pyramid, as there are more cards in play there.
	</para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>
